<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jhaarala&#39;s DASC 1104 Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on jhaarala&#39;s DASC 1104 Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>NHL Goal Data</title>
      <link>/2020/12/10/nhl-goal-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/12/10/nhl-goal-data/</guid>
      <description>Data In this project I will be examining NHL goal data using the game_goals.csv dataset from HockeyReference.com (they put out the other two datasets used in this post as well) that they put out after future hall-of-famer Alexander Ovechkin scored his 700th career goal. The data consists of 49384 observations of 25 variables. The variable season represents each NHL season from 2006 to 2018.
The second dataset I will be using is the season_goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NBA RAPTOR Ratings&#39; Predictive Ability</title>
      <link>/2020/12/09/nba-raptor-ratings-predictive-ability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/12/09/nba-raptor-ratings-predictive-ability/</guid>
      <description>Data library(tidyverse) RAPTOR_byteam_latest &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;latest_RAPTOR_by_team.csv&amp;quot;) RAPTOR_byplayer_hist &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;historical_RAPTOR_by_player.csv&amp;quot;) RAPTOR_byteam_hist &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;historical_RAPTOR_by_team.csv&amp;quot;) In this project, I am examining individual players’ impact on their team’s success using the latest_RAPTOR_by_team.csv dataset(s) from the fivethirtyeight website. The data consists of 808 observations of 23 variables. The variable pace_impact represents a player’s impact on team possessions per 48 minutes, so if it is positive that means that that player is helping to increase the pace by which their team plays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 18:38:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Jacob Haarala. I am currently an Honors Data Science student at the University of Arkansas in my freshman year. During my childhood I grew up parts in Wisconsin and Louisiana. I hope that someday this blog could help potentially springboard my professional career, and help me get some good job oppurtunities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
